

Hyeonmin Lee

Network Security Researcher



I am a Postdoctoral Research Associate in the Department of Computer Science at the University of Virginia, where I work with Prof. Yixin Sun. My research interests lie in network security including DNS security, Email security, and PKI/TLS. I have published five papers, three of which were published in top-tier conferences including USENIX Security and The Web Conference (formerly known as WWW). Also, I have participated in (or led) more than ten research projects with institutions such as Virginia Tech, Rochester Institute of Technology, University of Twente, SIDN Labs, NLnet Labs, etc. I have covered a variety of techniques in my research, such as DNS security (e.g., DNSSEC, DoT, DoH), Email security (e.g., STARTTLS), PKI, TLS, DANE, IoT, and edge computing.

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie in the field of **network security**, with a focus on identifying security issues in network systems and designing practical solutions to address them. In my research, I often utilize Internet measurement to identify potential security problems.

My current research focuses on areas including (but not limited to) DNS security, email security, and PKI/TLS. My research aims to identify potential security vulnerabilities in these systems and develop practical solutions to enhance their security.

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, (Seoul, South Korea)

Mar 2016 — Feb 2022

- o [Ph.D. Thesis] "Understanding the DANE Ecosystem in Email: How Is It Deployed and Managed?"
- o [Advisors] Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (Seoul National University) and Prof. Taejoong "Tijay" Chung (Virginia Tech)

B.S., Computer Science and Engineering, *Seoul National University*, (Seoul, South Korea) **Visiting Student, Information Technology**, *Uppsala University*, (Uppsala, Sweden)

Mar 2011 — Feb 2016

Fall 2014

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Research Associate, Dept. of Computer Science *University of Virginia*

Oct 2023 — Present Charlottesville, VA, United States

Postdoctoral Researcher, Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering Seoul National University

Apr 2022 — Sep 2023 Seoul, South Korea

- o [Web and DANE] Studid how the Web ecosystem will be changed if the Web adopts the DANE protocol (Achievement Grant).
- o [STARTTLS] Investigated how to prevent STARTTLS downgrade attacks.
- □ [DNS and TLS] Analyzed how DNS can be exploited to reduce the TLS handshake time (Achievement Publication [C4]).
- o [DNS and PKIX] Studied how we can guarantee the integrity of DNS records using PKIX certificates.

Technical Research Personnel*, Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering Seoul National University

Mar 2019 — Feb 2022

Seoul, South Korea

- *Technical Research Personnel is a form of military service (a combination of military service with a Ph.D. program) in which the service is fulfilled by carrying out research on technology. While fulfilling the service, I participated in or led several research projects; Please note that I had not been involved in any military-related projects.
- o [Email and DANE] Measured how DANE is deployed in the SMTP ecosystem (Achievements Publications [C2, P1]).
- o [Email and DANE] Investigated the underlying reasons for the DANE mismanagement (Achievement Publication [C3]).

Visiting Student, The Center for Cybersecurity

May 2019 — Aug 2019

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY, United States

o [Email and DANE] Analyzed DANE to measure its deployment in the real-world (Achievements - Publications [C2, P1]).

PUBLICATIONS

[C4] ZTLS: A DNS-based Approach to Zero Round Trip in TLS handshake

TheWebConf'23

Sangwon Lim, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Hyunsoo Kim, Hyunwoo Lee, and Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon *In Proceedings of the ACM Web Conference 2023 (formerly WWW)*, Austin, United States, Apr 2023

[C3] Under the Hood of DANE Mismanagement in SMTP

USENIX Security'22

Hyeonmin Lee, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung In Proceedings of the 31st USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, United States, Aug 2022

[C2] A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email

USENIX Security'20

Hyeonmin Lee, Aniketh Gireesh, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung *In Proceedings of the 29th USENIX Security Symposium*, Boston, United States, Aug 2020

[C1] Development of Cellular Core Network Enabling Network Function Virtualization **Hyeonmin Lee**, Junghwan Song JCCI'18

The 28th Joint Conference on Communication and Information, Yeosu, Korea, May 2018

- [J1] TwinPeaks: An Approach for Certificateless Public Key Distribution for the Internet and Internet of Things **Computer Networks** Eunsang Cho, Jeongnyeo Kim, Minkyung Park, **Hyeonmin Lee**, Chorom Hamm, Soobin Park, Sungmin Sohn, Minhyeok Kang, Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon *Elsevier Computer Networks* (SCI-E)
- [P1] A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email USENIX Security'22

 Hyeonmin Lee, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung

 Poster Session in the 31st USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, United States, Aug 2022
- [D] Understanding the DANE Ecosystem in Email: How Is It Deployed and Managed?

 Hyeonmin Lee

Ph.D. Thesis

Ph.D. Thesis, The Graduate School, Seoul National University, Feb 2022

GRANTS

A Study for the Future-oriented DANE-based Web Architecture to Solve Problems in the Current TLS-based Web Ecosystem Primary Investigator Sep 2022 — Aug 2023

(Funded by Basic Science Research Program - National Research Foundation of Korea, $\$60,000,000 \approx \$46,000$)

- [Project Goal] At present, the DANE protocol is mainly used for SMTP server authentication in mail transfers. In this project, I examined the potential impact of adopting the DANE protocol for peer authentication on the Web ecosystem.
- o [Keywords] Web, Transport Layer Security (TLS), Authentication, DANE.
- o [Role] As a primary investigator, I conducted the overall project.

RESEARCH PROJECT EXPERIENCE (SELECTED)

Research on Secure DNS and Privacy aware Packet Filtering Technology

System Designer/ Programmer

Aug 2022 — Jul 2023

(Funded by Samsung Electronics)

- o [Project Goal] This project aimed to design a secure DNS environment for mobile devices. The project involved analyzing the performance of DNS over TLS (DoT) and DNS over HTTPS (DoH) in the mobile environment, as well as designing a packet filtering mechanism based on DNS packets.
- ∘ [Keywords] Domain Name System (DNS), DNS over TLS (DoT), DNS over HTTPS (DoH), Packet filtering.
- [Role] As a postdoc, my role was to design a system that filters packets using DNS packets and to implement it on BIND9.

Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis

Project Manager/System Designer/Programmer

Mar 2021 — Nov 2021

(Funded by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC))

- [Project Goal] This project aimed to develop a system for detecting anomalies or attacks in IoT networks and generating evidence for digital forensics by collecting IoT network traffic.
- o [Keywords] IoT network, Network security, Machine learning, Abnormal detection, DDoS.
- o [Role] As a doctoral student, I took on the role of project manager and designed the entire system aimed at detecting anomalies or attacks in IoT networks. In addition to designing the system, I implemented an autoencoder model to distinguish between abnormal and normal IoT network traffic.

Versatile Network System Architecture for Multi-dimensional Diversity

Project Manager System Designer/ Programmer Mar 2020 — Dec 2020

Apr 2016 — Mar 2020

(Funded by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP))

- [Project Goal] This project aimed to design a network architecture that covers diverse network devices, services, or resources, especially, in the edge network (Related achievements Patent [1, 2, 3]).
- o [Keywords] Edge/Cloud computing, Mobility, In-network caching, Trustworthiness.
- o [Role] As a doctoral student, I took on the role of project manager between March 2020 and December 2020. One of my major contributions to the project was devising and testing a naming system that could effectively express a wide range of network devices, services, or resources in the edge network. Additionally, I implemented an ID resolver that was capable of handling the mapping between IDs and resources, including tasks such as ID allocation and mobility handling.

PATENTS

Method for Performing Mutual Authentication in Communication using Locator ID Separation Protocol, Apparatus, and System for Performing the Same

Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, Hyeonmin Lee, Hyunwoo Lee

- o Registration No. 10-2476081
- o South Korea, Dec 2022

· Network System and Method for Performing Message Security Thereof

Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, Hyunwoo Lee, Myungchul Kwak, Hyeonmin Lee, Junghwan Lim, Yoojung Shin

- o Registration No. 10-2265611
- o South Korea, Jun 2021

· Communication Method Based on Integrated Flat ID and System

Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, Hyunwoo Lee, Myungchul Kwak, Hyeonmin Lee, Dongjun Lee, Hyunchul Oh

- o Registration No. 10-2023115
- o South Korea, Sep 2019

AWARDS & FELLOWSHIPS

Seoul National University Alumni Association Scholarship, Kwanak Corporation	Fall 2018
Lecture/Research Scholarship, Seoul National University	Spring 2016
Exchange Student Program at Uppsala University	Fall 2014
Seoul National University Alumni Association Scholarship, Kwanak Corporation	Fall 2013
National Scholarship for Science & Engineering, Korea Student Aid Foundation	Spring 2011

TALKS & PRESENTATIONS

DNS-OARC 40, Online, "Guaranteeing the integrity of DNS records using PKIX Certificates"	Feb 2023
APNIC Blog, Online post, "Under the hood of DANE mismanagement in SMTP"	Sep 2022
USENIX Security Symposium, Boston, "Under the Hood of DANE Mismanagement in SMTP"	
USENIX Security Symposium, Online, "A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email"	Aug 2020

SKILLS

Tools and Languages	Python (proficient), C/C++, Java, Go, Spark, Hadoop, Git, 蹈EX, Linux OS
Knowledge Background	DNS, DNS Security (i.e., DNSSEC, DoT, DoH), SMTP, Email Security (i.e., STARTTLS), PKI, DANE, TLS, Net-
	work Protocols (i.e., TCP, IP, HTTP, HTTPS, QUIC), IoT, Edge computing

Communication English, Korean (native)

REFERENCES

Yixin Sun (ys3kz@virginia.edu)

o Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science, University of Virginia, Charlottesville, VA, United States

Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (tkkwon@snu.ac.kr)

o Professor, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Taejoong (Tijay) Chung (tijay@vt.edu)

o Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA, United States

A Study for the Future-oriented DANE-based Web Architecture to Solve Problems in the Current TLS-based Web Ecosystem

Primary Investigator Sep 2022 — Aug 2023

 $(Funded \ by \ \textit{Post-Doctoral Domestic and Overseas Training Program - National Research Foundation of Korea, \ \$60,000,000 \approx \$46,000)$

- [Project Goal] At present, the DANE protocol is mainly used for SMTP server authentication in mail transfers. In this project, I
 examined the potential impact on the Web ecosystem if the DANE protocol were to be adopted for peer authentication in
 communications.
- o [Role] Primary Investigator

Research on Secure DNS and Privacy aware Packet Filtering Technology

Aug 2022 — Jul 2023

(Funded by Samsung Electronics)

- [Project Goal] This project aimed to design a secure DNS environment for mobile devices, which includes analyzing the performance of DoT/DoH in the mobile environment, designing a packet filtering mechanism based on DNS packets.
- o [Role] System Designer / Programmer

Research on Traceability for Data Stability on Cloud-edge Lifecycle

Apr 2020 — Dec 2021

(Funded by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP))

- [Project Goal] This project aims to develop a technology that ensures the stability and traceability of cloud data by leveraging Trusted Execution Environment (TEE).
- o [Role] Programmer

Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis

Mar 2021 — Nov 2021

(Funded by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC))

- [Project Goal] This project aims to develop a system that detects anomalies (or attacks) in IoT networks and generates evidence for digital forensics by collecting IoT network traffic.
- o [Role] Project Manager (Lab.) / System Designer / Programmer

Versatile Network System Architecture for Multi-dimensional Diversity This project aims to design a network architecture that covers diverse network devices, services, or resources, especially, in the edge network.

Apr 2016 — Dec 2020 (Funded by *Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP)*)

- [Project Goal] This project aims to design a network architecture that covers diverse network devices, services, or resources, especially, in the edge network.
- o [Role] Project Manager (Lab.) / System Designer / Programmer

Research on GPU Acceleration for Fully Homomorphic Encryption

Feb 2020 — Nov 2020

(Funded by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC))

- [Project Goal] This project aims to accelerate Fully Homomorphic Encryption (FHE) techniques using GPUs, including research that reduces CPU-GPU interaction and CPU-to-GPU memory dependencies.
- o [Role] Programmer

Research on Distributed Web Structure and Counterplan

Aug 2019 — Nov 2019

- (Funded by Korea Internet and Security Agency (KISA))
- [Project Goal] The project aims to analyze trends in the Distributed Web and draw a blueprint for applying it to the domestic web ecosystem.
- o [Role] Researcher

Research on Trust and Security Scheme for Interconnection of Heterogeneous Networks

Sep 2018 — Nov 2018

(Funded by Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI))

- [Project Goal] The purpose of this task is to analyze the authentication and networking methods of diverse IoT products and to propose a new framework to solve problems arising in heterogeneous network environments.
- o [Role] Researcher

Research and Development of Open 5G Reference Model

Aug 2016 — Feb 2019

(Funded by Giga KOREA Foundation)

- o [Project Goal] This project aims to develop an open-source 5G reference model and implement a simulator to test it.
- o [Role] System Designer / Programmer

Development of Network Security Acceleration for Next-generation Low-power SoC

Jul 2015 — Dec 2015

(Funded by Samsung Electronics)

- [Project Goal] This project aims to design a system that reduces the overhead of the TLS handshake through a delegation in communications among low-power devices.
- o [Role] Programmer